Have you ever wondered how analysts sift through vast databases to find just the right information?
In this video, we’ll explore the powerful logical operators in SQL or Structured Query Language.
Logical Operators are a part of a family of operators in SQL.
Today we'll learn about 3 most commonly used operators.
Let's start with AND.
When we use AND, all conditions must be true for a row to be included in the result set.
Imagine you need to find customers who are both Sales Rep and from the city of London—AND does the trick!
It retrieves only those customers who are both Sales Rep and from London.
Now, meet OR—it's the "either-or" operator.
If any condition is true, it gets a ticket to the result set.
Whether you're looking for customers from Seattle or those who are Owners, OR lets you do it in a single query!
Finally there's NOT. If a condition is false, NOT makes it true.
Want to find customers who aren't Sales Rep or Sales Managers? NOT is your go-to operator!
You can combine these operators to create powerful, complex queries.
Let’s recap -
Logical operators allow us to filter data based on specific conditions.
The AND operator retrieves data only if all the conditions are TRUE.
With the OR operator, we can retrieve data if any of the conditions are TRUE.
When we use NOT, we get data that is not TRUE according to a specific condition.
In conclusion, logical operators—AND, OR, NOT—give us precise control over the database queries, making SQL a versatile tool for data management and analysis.
Thanks for watching.